日本語字幕仕上げ：光川  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
Hey! The one with the captain armband is-
おい！　キャプテンマークつけてんのって…
どうなってんだよ！
やだなあ　これ
I don't like this.
無駄に装飾品つけてる下品なやからみたいでさ
I feel like a hoodlum, wearing this armband.
へえ　ジーノがキャプテンで７番は見た事ない若手か
Gino's the captain?
And No.7 is a rookie...
面白そうじゃん　たつみ…達海監督
Interesting indeed, Tatsumi.
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
hold on tight
my story…
forever
ハハハハ　超ウケる！
That's hilarious! Exiling Murakoshi and replacing him with that no-good Gino as captain.
村越さん外して　よりによって一番ありえない　ジーノがキャプテンなんて
ねらってるとしか思えないっス
There must be some conspiracy going on!
せいぜい勝つ気でいなよ
Having that winning mentality...
想像するだけなら自由だからね
And then coming out at us...
ま　僕が主役ってのには
I'm sure nobody will mind me being in the spotlight, eh?
そんなに抵抗ないけどね
そんな事　誰も言ってねえだろ
Nobody gives a damn anyway.
タッツミも　来たばっかりで寂しいだろうしさ
Tatsumi must be quite lonesome, since he just arrived back.
ちょっとくらい　乗っかってあげるのも　悪くないかもねぇ
I suppose we can entertain the gaffer for a bit.
あの作戦で　本当にうまくいくんでしょうか?
Are you sure your plan's gonna work?
赤崎や世良はともかく
I won't question Akasaki's and Sera's inclusion, but I feel it's still too early for Tsubaki...
私には　椿はまだ…
松ちゃん
Macchan.
９０分間　ここは戦場だ
This will be a battlefield for the next ninety minutes.
自分たちを信じろ
You will just have to trust the lads.
迷ってたら
The moment one's resolve wavers, he'll get swallowed up by his opponents.
食う前に食われちまうぜ
I'm really looking forward to this.
楽しみだなぁ
Yeah.
見せてくれ　達海
Show us what you're made of, Tatsumi.
Show us how you'll use that footballing brain of yours to bring the champions down to their knees!
お前のサッカーで チャンピオンチームを黙らせるところを
彼が　タッツミーの言ってた例のクロアチア人ね
That should be the Croatian that Tatsumi mentioned about.
やあ　君が僕の今日のデートの相手かい？
So, you will be my date for today, huh?
三雲です
Mikumo's the name.
僕ってさぁ　自分はフラフラすんの好きなんだけど
Though I'm not one to tolerate partners that have multiple affairs...
相手の浮気とか許せないたちでさぁ
しっかりと　ついて来れる？ミック
Will you be loyal enough to stick close to me, Miku?
ナイスカット
Nice interception, Shironishi!
潰せ！
持田！
Mochida!
Mochida...
持田…
日本代表選手の中でもやっぱり　こいつは何かが違う
A Japanese international...
He's definitely a cut above the rest.
通ったぞ！
They've succeeded in their long pass!
いきなり　やられてんじゃねえぞお前ら
Don't get thumped so early in the game, you guys!
What a pity!
残念！
That was close!
あっぶねぇ！
集中しろ　集中！
Get your acts together, lads!
持田にはもっと厳しくいけ！
Shackle down Mochida!
It's so dangerous whenever the ball gets to Mochida.
やっぱり持田に渡ると怖いですねぇ
ヴィクトリの心臓か
The heart of Victory, eh?
ビビってたら　きりがない
It'll spell trouble if we are being overwhelmed by our opponents.
俺たちのやる事は１つだ
First up, just like previous years,
作戦その１
去年までと同じく
ボールを奪ったら
After wrestling back possession, you will focus all passes to Gino.
とにかく１回はジーノに預けること
Will this tactic really unlock Victory's defence?
本当に　あんな作戦で
ヴィクトリの守備を崩せるのか？
コッシ　　走らなくていいパスちょうだいよ
Koshi, you don't have to bust your guts just to pass me the ball.
No good! He will get double-teamed!
駄目だ　挟まれるぞ！
ザッキ　あげる
It's all yours, Zaki!
いいよザッキ　もらってあげるよ
It's okay, Zaki. Give me back the ball.
今期もやはりジーノが攻撃の起点か
So Gino will still be the centre of all attacks this season?
But like his nickname suggests, the Prince still continues to do whatever he likes.
しかし　王子のが付くほどのわがままぶり
キャプテンシーを発揮できるとも思えんが…
He's certainly not captain material in my opinion.
ジーノに変化があったのか
Or did Gino undergo some changes? Or maybe...
それとも…
From the right again?
あ　また右サイド！
何でシャリッチばかり？
Why are they focusing their attacks on Saric's side?
中央にパスを出すつもりなのか？
Is he thinking of passing the ball to the centre of the pitch?
惑わされるなぁ
I must not get side-tracked.
今は　ボールが集まる　この人だ
For now, the key man in attack is this guy.
チームを率いる印を巻いているこの人
He's upholding his resposibility as the captain. As an anchor man, I won't let him have his way!
おれつぶし屋の俺が好きにさせていいはずがない
いいのかい？　ミック
Is that really alright, Miku?
そんな！
Impossible! There wasn't anyone in that area behind me just now!
今　そのスペースには誰も…
目の前　空いてるぞ
The defence is cleared out.
ぶっちぎってこい　椿
Go forth, Tsubaki!
何だ　あいつ！
Who the hell's that guy?! He's fast!
速え！
周り！　サポート走れ！
People around him, provide support!
止めろよ　秋森
Hold him back, Akimori.
抜いた！
He's through! Furthermore, that defender is a Japanese international!
相手は日本代表だぞ
打たせるな！
Don't let him shoot! Cover up the shooting space!
コースをふさげ！
チッ…　狙いすぎた
I miscued it.
な…　何か　今
T-That was some good chemistry there.
いい形だったぞ
中盤の底が一瞬で駆け上がってきたのか？
How did he get into the centre area in a blink of an eye?
紹介するよ　ミック
Let me introduce them, Miku.
あれ　僕が飼ってる犬のバッキー
That is my adopted dog, Baki.
ま　君は気にせず僕についておいでよ
But don't mind him, just keep marking me.
何だ　ありゃ！　なんつう足してんだよ
What was that just now?
Is that the legs a human should have? What is he, an animal?
動物かっつうの？
やっぱり
As I expected, this ETU team led by Tatsumi is certainly interesting.
達海さんのＥＴＵおもしれえよ
どうしたんだ　椿のヤツ
What happened to Tsubaki?
キャンプの時は　いいとこなしで…
His performance was not up to par during our training camp...
ホント　わけ分かんないよなあいつ
He's definitely someone whom people can't understand.
でもね
However, that's our Tsubaki, Macchan.
それが椿なんだよ　松ちゃん
キャンプの最後の晩にねそいつが分かった
During the last day of our training camp...
I finally knew...
Aim, shoot and goal!
狙いどおりゴール！
Nice move!
いやあ　スゲーじゃん
お前が　そんなに楽しそうにサッカーができるとはねぇ
You're certainly having fun with the ball.
か…　監督
Manager?
あ　悪い悪い　邪魔するつもりはなかったんだけどさ
My bad, my bad. I didn't mean to disturb you.
せっかくだから俺も交ぜてくれよ　椿
How about letting me join in...
Tsubaki.
お前は　ドリブルからミドルシュート
You just have to dribble, and then do some mid-range shooting.
ペナルティーエリアの外からな
Make sure you shoot outside the penalty area.
俺はディフェンダーっていっても
As for me, I'll be standing here as defence.
ここら辺に突っ立ってるだけだから
よし　いつでも来い！
Alright! Come at me!
集中…
Concentrate... concentrate.
集中
恥ずかしいところ見られたけど
Though the manager saw an embarrassing side of me, this is my chance!
これはチャンスだ
このキャンプで失敗しまくったのを
I need to use this opportunity to atone for my dismal performance during the camp!
ここで挽回するんだ！
一番いいプレーを！
I need to...
I need to take this chance!
おいおい　外すにしても程があんだろ
Well, that's a bit too pathetic!
す　すいません！
Sorry!
落ち着け　落ち着け
Calm down, calm down. I just used too much force just now!
力むから　こうなるんだ
It's always due to this that I always fail!
何度もこれで失敗してきたろ
いつもどおり
自然体…　自然体
Take it easy...take it easy.
でも　監督に当たりでもしたら
But I'll probably leave a bad impression if I accidentally hit the manager!
絶対イメージ悪いよな
ふざけてる？
Are you kidding me?
あ…　いや
No! That not it!
とんでもない！
何やってんだ　俺！
What in the world am I doing?!
The manager's mad now. That's for sure!
監督　怒ってるよ
当然だよ
全力でやらなきゃ
I'll really have to do my best!
ゴールってこんな小さかったっけ？
Is the goalmouth really that small?
落ち着け！落ち着け！
Calm down...calm down!
次こそ！
The next one... I'll score the next one!
椿
Oh forget it, Tsubaki.
うん…　もういいや
No!
違うんス！
Why not?
何が？
Just one more time...give me another chance!
もう１回
もう１回お願いしやす！
Well, I have already known...
まあ　分かってたけどねぇ
お前が重度のチキンだって事はさ
You're such a coward...
しかし面白いヤツだなあ
...yet intriguing.
A little pressure is all it takes for your confidence to crumble.
ちょっとのプレッシャーで　あんな見事に自滅するとは
However, during the training match, you showed me the potential to beat Murakoshi.
でも　紅白戦で　お前は
村越をぶっちぎるほどの動きを見せた
チキンのお前が何であんなプレーができたわけ？
How can a coward like you show such great potential?
I...have had my fair share of good and bad moments.
俺…
乗れる時と乗れない時があって
In that match, Murakoshi urged me to do my best.
あの時は
村越さんが　全力でこいって言ってくれて
That's why I felt pumped up then.
それで多分　気分が乗れて…
Besides, your words...
それと…
監督の言葉
ジャイアント…
Giant...killing.
キリング
There he goes again!
また来た！
That guy!
あいつだ！
おっしゃ　ファウル！
That's a foul!
Hey! That's supposed to be a free kick!
フリーキックよこせ
Manager, before the training match, you mentioned,
監督
紅白戦の前に言ったんです
"As long as you win, your position in the squad will change immensely."
勝てば　お前たちの立場は変わる
"This will be your first step towards giant killing."
ジャイアントキリングの始まりだって
I...
俺…
変わりたいんス
...want to change!
I have always hated this side of me since years ago.
嫌なんです　自分の事が昔から
I'm totally useless.
…情けなくて
Feeling mad about myself.
自分で自分に腹が立って…
Feeling gutted.
悔しくて…
Although I know that in my heart...
こんなんじゃ駄目なの分かってんスけど
I can't go on like this forever.
But...
でも…
All you need to do is remain like this.
それでいいよ　お前
I heard you've been doing image training.
イメージトレーニングなんだって？
Almost all the time, you will stay back to train by yourself after practice.
昔から練習後
１人でボール蹴ってたらしいじゃん
How did you know that?
何で　それ…
I learnt that from your middle school coach when I phoned him up.
電話で聞いた
お前の　中学高校ん時の　サッカー部の先生に
As well as the coach from the amateur league.
サテライト見てたコーチにもね
From the beginning, you have always wanted to strengthen your resolve.
長年　自分を変えたいと思ってきたその思い
It has already become a strength of yours.
お前のスゲーパワーになってるよ
You don't have a good track record in the past.
お前には過去の実績は何もねえ
Despite that, you still made it to the regular team in a top club.
それでもお前は　今プロクラブのトップチームにいる
お前を育てた人たちはみんな
All your coaches said that.
同じような事を言ったよ
１０回のうち９回はヘマをするが
Though you have failed nine times out of ten,
That one time you succeeded, you have managed to make people sit up and take notice.
たった１回
輝かしいプレーですべての人を魅了する
And those people whose attention you've caught have always been right behind you.
お前に魅せられた人たちが
ここまでお前の背中を押したんだ
お前の実力だ　椿
That's because you have the potential, Tsubaki.
そのまま行け
So do your best, no matter how many times you fail.
何度でも　しくじれ
Conversely, all you need is that one time...
そのかわり
１回のプレーで　観客を酔わせろ
Make the spectators cheer for you.
敵の度肝を抜け
Have your opponents tremble in fear.
お前ん中の
Bring out the power of giant killing in you.
ジャイアントキリングを起こせ
Tsubaki's attacking ability is working very well.
椿の突破が効いてますね
Our opponent's defence are now sitting deep, which makes it easier to gather the ball at the centre.
向こうのディフェンスラインが下がってきて
中盤でボールを奪いやすい
Our strategy is gradually becoming effective.
こっちの作戦が形になってきた
さあ　そろそろ点取ろうぜ
Now, it's time to score some goals.
That legs of yours ain't half-bad.
いい足してんねぇ　君
It's the Japanese international, Mochida!
に…　日本代表の持田さん！
年いくつ？
How old are you?
Twenty!
二十歳です
ハハハ　若いなぁ
You're so young! You're just getting started. Do your best!
これからじゃん！
頑張れ
Yes.
However, this world is pretty cruel, you know.
ま　この世界は厳しいからね
Pay close attention from now on!
いろいろ気を付けることだよ
Make a good pass to me!
いいパス　ちょうだいよ
Come here, Miku!
おいで　ミック
Everything will be fine if you just stick to me.
僕についてくりゃ問題ない
It's this tactic again. All I have to do is pay attention to No.7's sudden breakthrough.
また　この形
警戒すべきは７番の飛び出し
No. The main threat is still this man's play making.
不いや　やはり　起点になっているこの人が　一番怖い！
三雲が行ったぞ　王子！
Mikumo's catching up, Prince!
よし！
Great! Let's go, Tsubaki!
上がれ　椿！
Crap!
くそ
Didn't I warn you a second ago?
さっき言ったろ
この世界は
This world's pretty cruel.
厳しいって
So do your best,
そのまま行け
No matter how many times you fail!
何度でも　しくじれ
Conversely,
そのかわり
All you need is that one time...
１回のプレーで観客を酔わせろ
Bring out the power of giant killing in you!
お前の中のジャイアントキリングを見せろ！
That's it!
来た
７番　椿
No.7, Tsubaki!
What?
何だ？
何なんだ　あいつは？
What's with that guy?
The one that should be marked out...is him!
止めなきゃいけないのはあいつだ！
Cover up the shooting space! Don't let him shoot!
コースをふさげ！
シュートを打たせるな！
I have to stop you!
止めてやる！
He's coming!
来た！
Yes, the fish fell for the bait.
よし　釣れた
That's disappointing, Miku.
哀れなミック
I have already warned you for the umpteenth time.
あんなに忠告したのに
Goal! ETU scored!
決めた　ＥＴＵ　先制だ
決めた
ＥＴＵ　先制だ
Good job, Gino!
でかした　ジーノ！
王子 王子…
Prince! Prince! Prince!
That's the little present I prepared for you, Tatsumi!
僕からタッツミーへのちょっとした就任祝いだよ
Changing your tactics so early in the game?
早速　修正してきやがったか?
You two will take turns to take out Gino.
ジーノのマークは２人で受け渡しながらやれ
The opponents wants both of you to mark Gino.
向こうの狙いは　ジーノ１人にお前たち２人がつく事だ
分かるな
Understand?
Tatsumi was able to see through us in such a short amount of time.
達海監督は
短い期間でよくウチを研究してるよ
What I'm saying is that he made use of Mikuno's pride.
三雲のプライドを利用されたんだよ
Gino, whom was man-marked by Mikuno.
三雲にマークされたジーノが
If he were to face Saric on his own,
ボールを持ったまま　シャリッチに向かえば
The opponent would be freed up of an extra player, leaving a huge gap in the centre of the pitch.
向こうは１人余った状態で
中央に大きなスペースができる
Therefore, we will have to man-mark a different person...
普通だったらマークをスイッチする場面を
若い三雲に　それはできんよ
However for the young Mikuno, he won't have left it like this.
この厚い選手層の中
As a regular of a great team, his pride won't allow him to do that.
マークマンとしてレギュラーを勝ち取ったプライドが邪魔をする
Moreover, the opponent's captain is right in front of his eyes.
それに　ただでさえ目立つ男が
今日は目の前でキャプテンマークを巻いているんだ
It wouldn't be a surprise if his attention had been diverted.
気を取られたとしてもしかたがなかろう
However, this is nothing but a fluke.
しかし　所詮は奇襲
We wouldn't be wavered that easily.
ウチが動じるレベルではない
Shiro!
シロさん
I'll be changing tactics for a bit.
俺のところで流れ変えますよ
I can get this!
取れる！
I didn't touch him just now!
俺　今　触ってないス！
イ　イエロ？
Yellow?
触ってましたか
Was there even contact?
Who knows.
分かんない
But the opponent was trying to challenge him.
でも誘われたのは確かだ
He definitely did a good job with it.
うまいな…　あいつ
The taker's Mochida, Dori!
蹴るのは持田だ　ドリさん
It will certainly be Mochida!
絶対　持田です
分かってるよ
Got it.
That said though, his kick...
分かっててもヤツの球は…
Damn, we conceded.
チッ　やられた
You've got find the way to believe
That Mochida is despicable!
carry on and carry on
That's why we have to counter!
Till you can see tomorrow
I can see that you guys aren't satisifed with just this.
I'll say "never look back"
Crap!
追い風を待って
Don't think about not losing!
そうchanceをのがすなら
How do you look at me as a player?
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
no tears,Yes Let it go！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough！(We'll go！)
限界追い越せ
行け キツイほど
heart in red
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Go on！(We'll go！)
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
やめられない
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough！(We'll go！)
共に乗り越えて 行け
見えるか It's daybreak there
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
予測できないだから
It's time to go
止められない